Noel Phyllis Birkby Papers, 1932-1994
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES
  - Individuals
    - Sidney Abbott, 1972-76, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 482)
    - Jerri Allyn, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 483)
    - Jane Alpert, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 484)
    - Ellen Perry Berkeley, 1974, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 485)
    - Nell Blaine, 1960-73, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 486)
    - Ivy Bottini, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 487)
    - Charlotte Bunch, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 488)
    - Caroling, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 489)
    - Phyllis Chesler, 1970-1992 (Box 30, Folder 490)
    - Judy Chicago, 1977, 1979, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 491)
    - Mary Daly, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 492)
    - Betsy Damon, 1982-84 (Box 30, Folder 493)
    - Diana Davies, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 494)
    - Frances Doughty, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 495)
    - Louise Fishman, 1982, 1992-93 (Box 30, Folder 496)
    - Bici Forbes, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 497)
    - Gisele Freund, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 498)
    - Midi Garth, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 499)
    - Barbara Hammer, 1978, 1994, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 500)
    - Bertha Harris, 1971-93, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 501)
    - Dolores Hayden, 1979-83, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 502)
    - Jeriann Hilderly (aka Jeritree), 1978, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 503)
    - Buffie Johnson, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 504)
    - Jill Johnston, 1969-80 (Box 30, Folder 505)
    - Rakhel Kafri, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 506)
    - Maria Karras, 1976-77 (Box 30, Folder 507)
    - Margrit Kennedy, 1980-85 (Box 30, Folder 508)
    - Roberta Kosse, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 509)
    - Audre Lorde, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 510)
    - Barbara Love, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 511)
    - Cynthia Macadams, 1973-83, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 512)
    - Muriel Magenta, 1978, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 513)
    - Artemis March, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 514)
    - Kate Millett, 1970-93, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 515)
    - Maricla Moyano, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 516)
    - Jean Mundy, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 517)
    - Marilyn Murphy, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 518)
    - Esther Newton, 1971, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 519)
    - Jane O'Wyatt, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 520)
    - Eleanor Pam, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 521)
    - Arlene Raven, 1982-87, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 522)
    - Jeanette Kathleen Rogers, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 523)
    - Lynda Simmons, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 524)
    - Alida Walsh, 1978, 1982, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 525)
    - Leslie Kanes Weisman
      - General, 1973-92, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 526)
      - Teaching materials, 1972-78, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 527)
    - Charleen Whisnant, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 528)
    - Jennifer Wyland, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 529)
  - Women
    - General, 1970-75 (Box 31, Folder 530)
    - Abortion, 1977, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 531)
    - Academia, 1972-73, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 532)
    - Amazons, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 533)
    - Artists, 1962-87, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 534-535)
    - Books, 1971-93, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 536)
    - Book catalogs/publishers
      - Miscellaneous, 1970-81, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 537)
      - Academy Press Limited/Academy Chicago Limited, 1980, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 538)
      - Come! Unity Press, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 539)
      - Crossing Press, 1982-85 (Box 32, Folder 540)
      - Daughters, Inc., 1973-77 (Box 32, Folder 541)
      - Diana Press, 1976, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 542)
      - Feminist Press, 1977, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 543)
      - First Things First, 1973, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 544)
      - Know, Inc., n.d. (Box 32, Folder 545)
      - Naiad Press, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 546)
      - Northwest Matrix, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 547)
      - Red Clay Books, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 548)
    - Bookstores, 1977, 1983, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 549)
    - Books, poetry, 1971-76 (Box 32, Folder 550)
    - Books
      - Spiderwomon's Lesbian Fairy Tales, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 551)
      - Miscellaneous, 1966-72, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 552)
    - Business cards, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 553)
    - Calendars, 1973-80, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 554)
    - Cerridwen (a salon in the arts), n.d. (Box 32, Folder 555)
    - Class and the women's movement, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 556)
    - Conferences
      - Miscellaneous, 1971-88, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 557)
      - "Feminist Perspectives on Pornography," San Francisco, CA, 17-19 Nov 1978: conference materials, transcription of talk (Box 33, Folder 558)
      - National Organization for Women Sixth Annual Conference, Washington, DC, 17-19 Feb 1973: conference materials (Box 33, Folder 559)
      - National Radical Feminist Conference, Pennsylvania, Aug 1975: correspondence (Box 33, Folder 560)
      - "Woman 1977: The Status of American Women," National Women's Conference, Houston, TX, 18-21 Nov 1977: conference materials (Box 33, Folder 561)
        [see also SERIES VII. PHOTOGRAPHS]
    - Consciousness raising groups
      - General, 1971-72, 1981, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 562)
      - Transcript of CR Group One session, "Bisexuality," Oct 1971 (Box 33, Folder 563)
      - Transcript of CR Group One session, "Butch/Femme," Oct 1971 (Box 33, Folder 564)
    - Education, 1971-80 (Box 33, Folder 565)
    - Entrepreneurs, 1973-76, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 566)
    - Europe, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 567)
    - Film, 1971-92, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 568-569)
    - Health, 1976-80, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 570)
    - Huntington (Mass.) Project, 1973, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 571)
    - Images of women, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 572)
    - Matriarchy, 1978, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 573)
    - Memorabilia, 1970-75, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 574)
    - Motherhood, 1970, 1973, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 575)
    - Music/songs, 1971, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 576)
    - National Women's Agenda, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 577)
    - Organizations
      - Miscellaneous, 1972-89, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 578)
      - Building Women, Inc., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 579)
      - Feminist Art Institute, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 580)
      - New York Radical Feminists, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 581)
      - Fifth Street Women's Building, 1970-71 (Box 34, Folder 582)
      - Matrix: A Place of Our Own, 1986-87, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 583)
      - New Environments for Women, Inc., 1974, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 584)
      - New York Feminist Art Institute, 1977-85, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 585)
      - Older Women's League (OWL), 1981-85, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 586)
      - Sagaris, A Multi Racial Feminist Institute, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 587)
      - The Woman's Building (Los Angeles), 1975-83, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 588)
      - Womanschool Adult Education Center, Inc., 1975 (Box 34, Folder 589)
      - Women's Design Center, Inc., 1973-75 (Box 34, Folder 590)
      - Women's Design Space, 1974, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 591)
      - Women's Development Corporation, 1980, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 592)
      - Women's History Research Center, Inc., 1976, 1979, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 593)
      - Women's Interart Center, 1972-83, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 594)
      - Women's Liberation Center, 1970-72, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 595)
      - Women's Neighborhood Builders/Developers, 1981, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 596)
    - Periodicals, 1972-84, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 597)
    - Political actions, 1970-84, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 598)
    - Pornography, 1979, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 599)
    - Psychology, 1970-75, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 600)
    - Sexuality, 1983, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 601)
    - Spirituality, 1976-78, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 602)
    - Theatre, 1972-76, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 603)
    - Vegetarianism, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 604)
    - Violence against women, 1971, 1978, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 605)
    - Women's Liberation, 1970-74, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 606)
    - Women's Skill Exchange Festival, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 607)
    - Women's Studies, 1971-82, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 608)
  - Homosexuality
    - General, 1970-90, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 609)
    - Memorabilia, 1971, 1981, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 610)
    - Gay Academic Union, 1973, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 611)
    - Health, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 612)
    - History/Archives, 1979-80, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 613)
    - Lesbian and Gay Directory of Services and Resources, New York Metropolitan Area, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 614)
    - Lesbian artists, 1977-78 (Box 35, Folder 615)
    - Lesbian Life Space, 1973, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 616)
    - Lesbian literature and publishing, 1976-78, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 617)
    - Lesbianism, 1970-89, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 618-619)
    - Lesbianism and Women's Liberation press conference, 7 Mar 1973 (Box 36, Folder 620)
    - National Gay Task Force, 1974, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 621)
    - Organizations, miscellaneous, 1971-89, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 622)
    - Periodicals, miscellaneous, 1972-76 (Box 36, Folder 623)
    - Radicalesbians of Philadelphia, 1971, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 624)
  - Buttons, pins (Box 37)
  - T-shirts (Box 38-39)
- SERIES VII. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Photographic prints
    - Personal
      - NPB, 1930s-90s (Box 40, Folder 625-629)
      - Family, 1930s-88 (Box 40, Folder 630)
      - Friends
        - Groups, 1940s-90s (Box 40, Folder 631-635)
        - Women's College of the University of North Carolina, 1950-54 (Box 40, Folder 636)
      - Groups at parties, 1980s-90s (Box 40, Folder 637-638)
      - Groups at Huntington, MA, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 639)
      - Groups at Millett Farm, 1980s-90s (Box 41, Folder 640-641)
      - Jan Crawford, 1975, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 642)
      - Louise Fishman, 1967, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 643)
      - Barbara Hammer, 1977-78, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 644)
      - Jill Johnston, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 645)
      - Naomi Katz, 1964-65, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 646)
      - Kate Millett, 1972, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 647)
      - Jane O'Wyatt, 1973, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 648)
      - Leslie Kanes Weisman, 1974, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 649)
      - Miscellaneous groups, 1986, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 650)
      - Gravesite, Ka boat, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 651)
      - Art by NPB, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 652)
      - Hand-painted canes by NPB, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 653)
      - Cats, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 654)
      - Swimming, 1950, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 655)
      - 51 Castle St., Great Barrington, MA, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 656)
      - 51 Market St., New York, NY, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 657)
      - Yale University and New Haven, CT, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 658)
    - Artistic photography
      - Miscellaneous, 1952-90, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 659)
      - Roller skating, Venice, CA, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 660)
      - Trapeze, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 661)
    - Architecture
      - Amethyst House, Bayley-Seton Hospital Halfway House for Women, 75 Vanderbilt Ave., Staten, Island, NY, FDC #3465, 1990, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 662-664)
      - Bellevue Environs study, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 665)
      - Bellomo, 7455 Soundview Ave., Southold, NY, 1985-87, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 666)
      - Bronx Children's Psychiatric Center, Adolescent Day Treatment Center, 1180 Rev. James Polite Blvd., Bronx, NY, FDC #3166, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 667)
      - Bronx Psychiatric Center, Community Residence, 2747 University Ave., Bronx, NY, FDC # 4722, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 668)
      - Cardamon Lane Condominiums, Little Ferry, NJ, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 669)
      - Cinnamon Court, Little Ferry, NJ, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 670)
      - Evergreen Ave. and Townline Rd., Hauppauge, NY, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 671)
      - Fox/Whitby, Manhattan, 1987, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 672)
      - Fox/Whitby, Long Island, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 673)
      - Jacobs, 51 8th Ave., Sea Cliff, NY, 1973, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 674)
      - Johnston, Cutchogue, Southold, NY, 1985-89 (Box 42, Folder 675-677)
      - Knowlton, River Rd., Point Pleasant, PA, 1988-89 (Box 43, Folder 678)
      - Leser, 129 West 12th St., New York, NY, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 679)
      - Lobel, Hedges Bank Drive, E. Hampton, NY, 1977, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 680)
      - Long Island University, Brooklyn Campus, Master Plan, 1966-68 (Box 43, Folder 681)
      - Long Island University, Brooklyn Campus, Library/Learning Center, 1966-70 (Box 42, Folder 682-683)
      - Maple Knoll Village, Springdale, OH, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 684)
      - New American House: competition submission, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 685)
      - Pilgrim Psychiatric Center, Community Residence, 201 Garden Place, W. Hempstead, NY, FDC #4846, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 686)
      - Pilgrim Psychiatric Center, Community Residence, 3531 Oceanside Rd., Oceanside, NY, FDC #4845, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 687)
      - Sokolow, Winding Rd., Ardsley, NY, 1986, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 688)
      - Spyer, 2 Fifth Ave., New York, NY, and 254 Tuckahoe Lane, South Hampton, NY, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 689)
      - Thu Duc Polytechnic University, Bien Hoa, Vietnam, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 690)
      - 670 Townline Rd., Hauppauge, NY, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 691)
      - Urban Homesteading Assistance Board, Single Room Occupancy residence, 334-336 Bergen St., Brooklyn, NY, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 692)
      - 2886/92 Valentine Ave., 1989 (Box 43, Folder 693)
      - Vaughan, 201 West 138th St., New York, NY, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 694)
      - Watering Place Resort Hotel, Roatan, Honduras, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 695)
      - Waterside Houses, east midtown Manhattan, NY, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 696-697)
      - Women's Rights National Historical Park, Seneca Falls, NY, competition submission: photos of site and environs, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 698)
      - Unidentified, 1968, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 699)
      - Computer generated images, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 700)
      - Gruzen and Partners projects, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 701)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 702)
    - Political
      - Marches/demonstrations, 1970s-90s (Box 44, Folder 703)
      - National Women's Conference, Houston, TX, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 704)
      - Women's Encampment for a Future of Peace and Justice, Seneca Army Depot, NY, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 705)
    - Research, Speaking, and Writing
      - Elderly housing presentation, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 706)
      - Women and the Built Environment
        - Buildings by/for women, 1970s-80 (Box 44, Folder 707)
        - Danner House, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 708)
        - Fantasy drawings, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 709)
        - Women in Architecture symposium, Washington University, St. Louis, MO, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 710)
    - Teaching
      - University of Southern California faculty, c. 1979 (Box 45, Folder 711)
      - Samples of student work
        - Miscellaneous, 1980s (Box 45, Folder 712)
        - Berlin Wall Thesis Studio, 1987-88 (Box 45, Folder 713)
    - Travel
      - Unidentified, 1967, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 714)
      - Denmark, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 715)
      - Berlin, Germany, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 716)
      - Corn Palace, Mitchell, SD, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 717)
      - Cozumel, Mexico, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 718)
      - Honduras (?), n.d. (Box 45, Folder 719)
      - Vietnam, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 720)
      - Italy, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 721)
  - Negatives
    - 35mm, 1-69 (Box 46)
    - 35mm, 70-144 (Box 47)
    - 4x5, #200-231 (Box 48)
    - 4x5, #232-269 (Box 49)
  - Slides and transparencies
    - Architecture
      - Student Work, 1964-66, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 722)
      - Projects
        - A-N, 1973, 1986, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 723)
        - Jacobs, Johnston, 1971-72, 1985-88 (Box 50, Folder 724)
        - Leeds, 1975, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 725)
        - Lobel, 1977, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 726)
        - Long Island University, 1973-77, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 727)
        - T-Z, unidentified, 1973-87, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 728)
      - Miscellaneous, 1963, 1967, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 729)
      - Expo '67, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 730)
      - Soleri, Cosanti Foundation, Scottsdale, AZ, c. 1969 (Box 50, Folder 731)
      - Watts Towers, Los Angeles, CA, c. 1969 (Box 50, Folder 732)
    - Art by NPB and others, 1973-93, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 733)
    - Personal
      - Animals/pets, 1970, 1975, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 734)
      - 51 Market St., 1974, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 735)
      - Yale University [?], 1966, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 736)
      - Family [?], 1967-69, 1984, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 737)
      - Noel Phyllis Birkby, c. 1954-c. 1978 (Box 51, Folder 738)
      - Individuals
        - Miscellaneous, 1967-82, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 739-740)
        - Barbara Hammer and NPB, c. 1978-79, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 741)
        - Bertha Harris and Jennifer Wyland, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 742)
        - Jill Johnston, 1972-73 (Box 52, Folder 743)
        - Naomi Katz, 1964, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 744)
        - Alberta Ming Chi Wang, 1972, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 745)
        - Black and white photographs of friends, copies, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 746)
      - Groups, 1972-83, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 747)
      - Groups at Huntington, MA, 1972-73 (Box 52, Folder 748)
      - Groups at Millet Farm, 1972-93, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 749)
      - Groups, miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 750)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 751)
    - Political
      - 1971-77 (Box 53, Folder 752)
      - Gay Pride March, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 753)
      - National Women's Conference, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 754)
      - 1977-82 (Box 53, Folder 755)
      - Women's Encampment for a Future of Peace and Justice, Seneca Army Depot, NY, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 756)
      - Undated, unidentified (Box 53, Folder 757)
    - Research, Speaking, and Writing
      - Elderly housing
        - Teaching slides, 1975, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 758)
        - Plans and drawings, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 759)
        - Scandinavia, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 760)
      - Women and the Built Environment
        - Workshops, miscellaneous, 1973, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 761)
        - Workshop, "Kvinner, Natur, Rom," Oslo, Norway, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 762)
        - Fantasy drawings, 1977-79, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 763)
        - Slide lecture I, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 764)
        - Slide lecture II, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 765)
        - Lecture slides, misc., n.d. (Box 54, Folder 766)
        - Buildings by women
          - Miscellaneous, 1979-82, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 767)
          - Wholeo, 1973-76, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 768)
        - Women in Design: The Next Decade conference, Women's Building, Los Angeles, CA, 20-21 Mar 1975 (Box 54, Folder 769)
    - Artistic photography
      - Miscellaneous, 1966-83, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 770)
      - Mobile homes, 1975, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 771)
      - Nature, 1969-83, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 772)
      - Nature/beach, 1962-63, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 773)
      - New York City, 1964, 1972, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 774)
    - Teaching
      - Miscellaneous, 1975-78, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 775)
      - Design lecture slides, 1977, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 776)
      - Women's School of Planning and Architecture: fantasy drawings, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 777)
    - Travel
      - Bahamas, 1971-72 (Box 55, Folder 778)
      - England, c. 1960s (Box 55, Folder 779)
      - France [?], 1984, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 780)
      - Germany, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 781)
      - Germany: Berlin Wall, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 782)
      - Holland, 1984, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 783)
      - Italy, 1992, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 784)
      - Mexico, 1954-55, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 785-786)
      - Scandinavia, 1982, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 787)
      - Sri Lanka, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 788)
      - United States
        - General, 1970-84, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 789)
        - Canyon de Chelly, AZ, c. 1969 (Box 56, Folder 790)
        - Olympics, Los Angeles, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 791)
      - Vietnam, 1973
        - Slide lecture (Box 57, Folder 792)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 57, Folder 793)
      - San Genero, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 794)
- SERIES VIII. FILMS AND VIDEOTAPES
  All original audiovisual material is closed--access to audiovisual materials may first require production of research copies.
  - Written material
    - General and miscellaneous, 1972, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 795)
    - "Architectural Barriers to Women, Mothers with Young Children": introduction, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 796)
    - The Thanks be to Grandmother Winifred Foundation grant materials, 1993-94, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 796a)
    - "Head Change": notes, 1977, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 797)
    - "Listen!"/"The Second Wave" (proposed film on the women's liberation movement)
      - American Film Institute Independent Filmmaker Program funding applications, 1977-78 (Box 58, Folder 798)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 799-780)
      - Interview notes, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 781)
      - Interview transcripts
        - June Arnold (Box 58, Folder 782)
        - Charlotte Bunch (Box 58, Folder 783)
        - Robin Morgan (Box 58, Folder 784)
        - Esther Newton and Kathryn McHargue (Box 58, Folder 785)
        - Sue Perlgut (Box 58, Folder 786)
        - Carole Rosenthal (Box 58, Folder 787)
        - Dinah Utah and Nancy Johnson (Box 58, Folder 788)
        - Shirley Walton (Box 58, Folder 789)
    - Washington Square Park, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 790)
  - Films
    [see Appendix for descriptive list of films]
    (In-house use copies of films are available where noted (see box 72a)]
    - Architecture
      - Bronx House, Davis Brody (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Chicago (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Davis Brody and Associates (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - "Davis Brody Buildings" 10/71 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - "Davis Brody Building/1 Foot of Naomi Fatt" (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Hampshire College (Box 59, Folder 6-7A)
      - Laundromats, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - "LIU Library Model Making" (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - "LIU" (Box 59, Folder 10)
      - "Soleri" Watts Towers [?] Pouring Foundation (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - Soleri? Foundation pouring (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - Soleri, c. 1969? (Box 59, Folder 13)
      - Soleri, Sandy [?] (Box 59, Folder 14)
      - Soleri (Box 59, Folder 15)
      - Space Center Assembly Building (Box 59, Folder 16)
      - "Waterside Site/Yale shots" (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Art Films
      - "A&P Broome St./Ice Skate," 1962 (Box 60, Folder 18)
      - "A&P," Market St., 8/6/60 (Box 60, Folder 19)
      - "Ann and Sue," summer 1970 (Box 60, Folder 20)
      - "Auto Show" (Box 60, Folder 21)
      - "Backyard" (Box 60, Folder 22)
      - Backyard, 1979 (Box 60, Folder 23)
      - "Beach" (Box 60, Folder 24)
      - "Beach--Footprints" Flotsam 8/66 (Box 60, Folder 25)
      - Beach House 7/69 (Box 60, Folder 26)
      - "Beach Walk B.H.?" (Box 60, Folder 27)
      - "Beach With Dogs--Sagaponack" (Box 60, Folder 28)
      - "Bici's Divorce" (Box 60, Folder 29)
      - "BMT//Bridge" (Box 60, Folder 30)
      - "City Island, Women," 8/71 (Box 60, Folder 31)
      - "Clark Ferebee House" (Box 60, Folder 32)
      - "Clark/Ferebee, pigeons near Macy's" Herald Square, 5/70 (Box 60, Folder 33)
      - Dogs (Box 60, Folder 34)
      - "Drive" (Box 60, Folder 35)
      - Fantasy Film, Dream, Forbes, Birkby (Box 60, Folder 36)
      - "Fibishes" / Fall Foliage Family, 11/68 (Box 60, Folder 37)
      - Flowers, Stamford (Box 60, Folder 38)
      - Frances/Water, etc. @ Lynda's (Box 60, Folder 39)
      - "Head Change"
        - completed film [?] (Box 61, Folder 40)
          [In-house use copy available]
        - 16 mm elements, AB roll, magtrack (Box 61, Folder 41)
        - Slide out takes (Box 62, Folder 42)
        - Video out takes (Box 62, Folder 43)
        - Original footage (Box 62, Folder 44)
        - Out takes (Box 62, Folder 45)
        - Title roll (Box 62, Folder 46)
        - Out takes (Box 62, Folder 47)
        - Titles (Box 62, Folder 48)
        - A Roll (Box 62, Folder 49)
        - B Roll (Box 62, Folder 50)
        - Old title (Box 62, Folder 51)
        - Extra video (Box 62, Folder 52)
        - Titles (Box 62, Folder 53)
      - "Kite," 1971 (Box 62, Folder 54-55)
      - Lone Woman on Beach, 5/70 (Box 62, Folder 56)
      - Louise Fishman at the Beach (Box 62, Folder 57)
      - Love Letter (Box 62, Folder 58)
      - Mime (Box 62, Folder 59)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 62, Folder 60)
      - Nude Man at Beach (Box 62, Folder 61)
      - Rooftop Shooting (Box 62, Folder 62)
      - Scenery, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 63)